mauijim.com 2017-12-06

# Terms and Privacy Policy | Maui Jim

Aloha! As part of our O’hana, we at Maui Jim, Inc., Maui Jim USA, Inc., and other affiliated companies (collectively, the “Company”) believe strongly in protecting your privacy. That’s why we’re committed to the Direct Marketing Association’s “Privacy Promise to American Consumers.” We have agreed to:

  1. Provide customers with the notice of their ability to opt out of information rental, sale, or exchange with other marketers;
  2. Honor customers’ requests not to share their information with other marketers; and
  3. Honor customers’ requests not to receive mail, telephone, or other solicitations from the Company.

###### Collecting Your Information

In general, you can visit many of our web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. We may track the Internet domain address from which people visit us and analyze this data for trends and statistics, but individual users will remain anonymous, unless you voluntarily tell us who you are. Please be assured of the caution we use regarding the personal information you provide during the checkout process. This information is used to process your order and email you a confirmation of the order plus the shipping information. In addition, other internal uses for personal information received through our Web site may arise, which may include analyzing Web viewing trends and informing you of our new products to help enhance your shopping experience. In particular, we collect your information in the following ways:

_Browsing:_ If you visit this site but do not buy or transact with the Company in any way, the website will set cookies on your browser and will collect browsing information.

_Cookies:_ A "cookie" is a small amount of information stored on your hard drive which was sent to your Internet browser from a Web server. Cookies collect information on our behalf that will help us better understand how you navigate around the website and how we can target our products and services more effectively to suit your personal interests. In most instances, you are able to set your Internet browser to not accept cookies, or you can opt to be notified when a cookie is sent to your computer and then decide whether or not to accept it.

_Creating an Account or Logging In:_ You may choose to log into the site. If you do not have an account, you may create an account without placing an order. If you do create an account, you will be given the option to “opt in” to our email system: Email Opt In: If you select this option, indicating that you are interested in getting updates from the Company, you will submit your email information and be added to our distribution list. We do not share the distribution list with other companies. You will then receive multiple emails, unless and until you decide to opt-out from any of the messages you have received.

_Shopping (whether as a guest or as a registered account-holder):_ You must enter an email address to shop on our website. Your email will be stored and used to track your orders, along with billing, shipping, and order information. Your credit card information is tokenized and processed as described below.

_Submitting Repair Requests:_ You can submit a repair request online. If you choose to do so, your personal information relevant to the request will be required. Requesting Information About Events (Corporate Gifts Lead Generation, Golf Events Lead Generation): You can request information about events. If you select this option, you will be routed to the Email Opt In process described above.

###### How We Use Your Information

All personal information that we obtain about you will be recorded, used by us in accordance with current data protection legislation and this Policy. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing this personal information in one or more of the ways described in this Policy. We will primarily use your personal information to provide products and services to you, including sending you information/materials via e-mail or mail about products, offers and news we think could interest you, performing analyses of the website, for customer service purposes, and to complete online orders.

###### Third Party Cookies and Ads

Third parties may also collect information about you through our website. For example, third party analytics services use cookies and web beacons to help us compile statistics about our website and visitors to our website. We receive assurances from those third party analytics services that they will not collect or access any information that directly identifies you on our website. Other third parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you visit our website, for example, to display Maui Jim ads to you on third party websites and to deliver third party ads to our website and others as described below. Those links to other sites are not under our control. Those third party websites have their own policies regarding privacy, which we recommend that you read and review before visiting.

We may use third-party advertising companies to collect data when you visit our web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit <http://networkadvertising.org/> and <http://kenshoo.com/privacy-policy/>.

###### Google Analytics & Other Analysis Tools

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") and Hotjar, an web site usage analysis tool, provided by Hotjar Ltd. to collect data that allows us to improve the functionality of our websites and make them more useful to you and easier to use.

By visiting our website you acknowledge that you accept and consent to our privacy practices as well as those of Google Analytics and Hotjar as outlined or linked to in this policy.

_Hotjar:_ Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd. Hotjar honors generic “Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. For more information on Hotjar, how it collects data, what data it collects please and how to opt out of it collecting your information please read Hotjar's own privacy policy <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>.

_Google Analytics:_ Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en> to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics.

###### Sharing Your Information

Maui Jim, Inc., Maui Jim USA, Inc., and other affiliated companies do share information among themselves, and share information with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us. Also, it is possible that as our business develops, we might go through a business transition that could result in a change in ownership or control of your personal information. However, we will not ever sell, trade or rent any of your personally identifiable information to third party websites or companies for commercial purposes.

###### Securing Your Information & Credit Card Details

At mauijim.com, we utilize Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect the security of your credit card information. SSL encrypts your order information to avoid the decoding of that information by anyone other than mauijim.com. To make sure you are accessing our secure server before you submit your credit card information, please check your browser to see either an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending upon your browser), then SSL is active. To double-check for security, look at the URL or Location line of your browser during the order process. If you have accessed a secure server, the first characters of the address will change from "http" to "https". Some browser versions and some firewalls don't permit communication through secure servers like the ones we use to process orders at mauijim.com. If for any reason you cannot access the secure server, please feel free to place your order with us by phone at 1.888.666.5905.

Your credit card information submitted on the website is stored and processed by a third party which has contractually agree to comply with all rules, regulations, standards, or guidelines adopted or required by the credit card payment brands (including, without limitation, Visa, MasterCard, American Express, Discover, and JCB) or the Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council relating to privacy, data security, and the safeguarding, disclosure, and handling of Payment Instrument Information, including, without limitation, the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards, Visa’s Cardholder Information Security Program, Discover’s Information Security & Compliance Program, American Express’s Data Security Operating Policy, MasterCard’s Site Data Protection Program, Visa’s Payment Application Best Practices, the Payment Card Industry’s Payment Application Data Security Standard, MasterCard’s POS Terminal Security program, and the Payment Card Industry PIN Transmission Security program, in each case as they may be amended from time to time.

###### Protecting Children

The Company takes special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. Our website is a general audience site. We do not permit anyone who tells us that he/she is under the age of 18 to register with us. We also do not send email correspondence to anyone who tells us that they are under the age of 18 without their parent's consent. Children under the age of 18 should always ask their parents or guardians for permission before providing any personal information to anyone online. We urge parents and guardians to participate in their children's online activities and use parental control or other web filtering technology to supervise children's access to the web.

###### Policy Changes

If our information practices change in the future, we will notify you by posting the policy changes on our website and/or by communicating directly with you. We will notify you of any such change before we use your information in a manner not previously disclosed in our privacy policy. You will have the opportunity at that time to opt out of any new use of your information.

###### Third Party Websites

Our website may contain links to other sites that are not under our control. These websites have their own policies regarding privacy, which we recommend that you read and review before visiting. We provide these linked websites only for the convenience of our visitors and are not responsible for these sites.

###### Feedback From Our Visitors

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us at 1.888.666.5905. Many mahalos ("thank you" in Hawaiian) for your interest and cooperation!

### Terms of Use

By using this website (mauijim.com), you are agreeing to comply with the following Terms of Use, which form a legally binding contract between you and Maui Jim, Inc., Maui Jim USA, Inc., and affiliated companies (collectively, the “Company”). Please review these Terms of Use closely!

  1. **_Representations._** By accessing or using the website, you are representing to the Company that you are at least eighteen (18) years of age (or have consulted with and obtained permission from your parent or legal guardian).
  2. **_LIMITATION OF LIABILITY._** IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COMPANY BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH THE USE OF THE WEBSITE OR WITH THE DELAY OR INABILITY TO USE THE WEBSITE, WHETHER BASED IN CONTRACT, TORT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR OTHERWISE. NOTWITHSTANDING THE FOREGOING, TOTAL LIABILITY OF THE COMPANY FOR ANY REASON WHATSOEVER RELATED TO USE OF THE WEBSITE SHALL NOT EXCEED THE TOTAL AMOUNT PAID BY YOU TO THE COMPANY IN CONNECTION WITH THE SUBJECT MATTER OF THE PARTICULAR DISPUTE.
  3. **_Indemnity._** By using this application, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless the Company, and their directors, employees and agents, against any loss, damage, liability, cost, expense (including legal fees) asserted by any third party and arising from: (i) your use of and access to the website; (ii) your breach of any of these Terms of Use; and (iii) your infringement of any third party rights.
  4. **_Governing Law._** This agreement and all rights and obligations of the parties shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of Illinois without regard to its conflicts of laws provisions.
  5. **_Jurisdiction._** The parties agree to submit to the personal jurisdiction and sole and exclusive venue of the state and federal courts located in Peoria County, Illinois.

### Intellectual Property Notice

Welcome to the Maui Jim, Inc. Web Site ("Site"). Please review the following basic terms and conditions that govern your use of our Site. Please note that the services we provide you are subject to these terms, and that your use of our Site constitutes your agreement to follow and be bound by these terms.

Unless otherwise noted, all materials, including text, illustrations, photographs, designs, graphics, logos, button icons, images, audio clips, software, written and other material (collectively, the "Contents") are copyrights, trademarks, trade dress and/or other intellectual properties, owned, controlled or licensed by Maui Jim, Inc. (hereinafter “Maui Jim’s Intellectual Property”). U.S. and international copyright and trademark laws protect the Contents and the Site as a whole. Maui Jim’s Intellectual Property may not be used without our express written consent. We grant you a limited license to access and make personal use of this Site and not to download (other than page caching) or modify it, or any portion of it, except with the express written permission of Maui Jim, Inc. This license does not include any resale or commercial use of this Site or its Contents; any collection and use of any product listings, descriptions or prices; any derivative use of this site or its Contents; downloading or copying of account information for the benefit of another merchant; or any use of data mining, robots, or similar data gathering and extraction tools. This Site or any portion may not be reproduced, duplicated, copied, sold, resold, visited or otherwise exploited for any commercial purpose without our express written consent. You may not frame or utilize framing techniques to enclose any of Maui Jim’s Intellectual Property or other proprietary information (including images, text, page layout or form) of the Site without our express written consent. You may not use any metatags or any other "hidden text" utilizing our name, trademarks, service marks or any other of Maui Jim’s Intellectual Property without our express written consent. Any unauthorized use terminates the permission or license granted by us.

Unless otherwise noted, all trademarks, service marks, and trade names used herein, are trademarks or registered trademarks of Maui Jim, Inc. in the U.S. and certain jurisdictions, including but not limited to: MAUI, MAUI JIM, MAUI JIM (STYLIZED), MAUI JIM & PARROT DESIGN, MAUI EVOLUTION, MAUIREADERS, MAUIREADERS PLUS, MAUI PURE, MAUI ROSE, MAUIFLEX, MAUIGRADIENT, MYMAUI, POLARIZEDPLUS, POLARIZEDPLUS2, CLEARSHELL, COLOR LIKE YOU’VE NEVER SEEN IT, HCL, REFLECT YOUR BRILLANCE, TITANIUM ELITE, WELCOME TO COLOR, COLOR.CLARITY.DETAIL, MAUI JIM AUTHENTIC POLARIZEDPLUS2 and Design, THE WORLD’S MOST MEMORABLE GIFT EXPERIENCE and WWW.MAUIJIM.COM. POLAGE is a trademark of Austine Studios. GUY HARVEY is a trademark of Guy Harvey, Inc. PolarizedPlus2 lens technology is covered by U.S. Patent No. 6,145,984. Maui Jim Sunglasses may be covered by one or more of the following patents: U.S. Patent Nos. D481059; D481060; D488829; D508514; D539828; D543230; 9,671,622; 7,717,557; and 6,145,984.
